Guide to the Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Files, 1877-1970; Series IV; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  - Volume VI
    - Documents
      - Transcript of information Edwin J. Beinecke sent to John Howell Books about portrait, undated (Box 76, Folder 1961)
      - Transcript of letter of Feb. 1876 to Friend from M. Munkacsy about a painting he would like to exhibit. Pencil notes that it is a copy of letter for sale by Howell., undated (Box 76, Folder 1962)
      - List of things for sale, [1941 September 15] (Box 76, Folder 1963)
      - List of G[ertrude] Hill's friend's and business acquaintances, undated (Box 76, Folder 1964)
      - Note on 125 letters to Sidney Colvin from Robert Louis Stevenson, undated (Box 76, Folder 1965)
      - Inventory of Osbourne's Stevenson library, undated (Box 76, Folder 1966)
      - Note on Osbourne collection photos of an oil painting of RLS at Saranac by Dwight Franklin, undated (Box 76, Folder 1967)
      - Gertrude Hill's autograph inventory of Osbourne collection, undated (Box 76, Folder 1968)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Club ephemera, 1925, undated (Box 76, Folder 1969)
  - Other Material
    - Bibliographical notes, undated (Box 77, Folder 1970)
    - Bibliographical notes, undated (Box 78, Folder 1971)
    - Catalogs and lists, 1934-1970, undated (Box 79, Folder 1972-1977)
    - Clippings, 1893-1949, undated (Box 79, Folder 1978)
    - Correspondence, 1915-1965, undated (Box 79, Folder 1979)
    - Financial records and correspondence, 1924-1939, undated (Box 79, Folder 1980-1982)
    - Gertrude Hills' notes, undated (Box 79, Folder 1983-1987)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 80, Folder 1988)
    - Lists of Robert Louis Stevenson material, 1951 (Box 80, Folder 1989)
    - Magnifying glass, undated (Box 80, Folder 1990)
    - Manuscript fragments, 1931, undated (Box 80, Folder 1991)
    - Photographs, 1877-1880, undated (Box 80, Folder 1992-1993)
    - Photostats of material used in "Gertrude Hills' book", undated (Box 80, Folder 1994)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 80, Folder 1995)
    - Preliminary list for Edwin J. Beinecke's collector's files, undated (Box 80, Folder 1996)
    - Printed ephemera, 1946, undated (Box 80, Folder 1997)
    - Spoon, undated (Box 80, Folder 1998)
    - Thank you letters for Robert Louis Stevenson's Handwriting, 1940-1941 (Box 80, Folder 1999-2002)
    - Thanks you letters for The Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson, 1939-1940 (Box 80, Folder 2003)
- Oversize, 1864-1966; 22.7; (51 boxes)
  Oversize materials are subdivided for bound volumes and material housed in oversize boxes.
  - Bound Volumes
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1868-1876 (Box 81, Folder 2004)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1877-1880 (Box 82, Folder 2005)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1880-1882 (Box 83, Folder 2006)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1881-1883 (Box 84, Folder 2007)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1883-1884 (Box 85, Folder 2008)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1884 (Box 86, Folder 2009)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1885-1888 (Box 87, Folder 2010)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1888-1889 (Box 88, Folder 2011)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1890 (Box 89, Folder 2012)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1891-1892 (Box 90, Folder 2013)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Charles Baxter (In Series I), 1893-1894 (Box 91, Folder 2014)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Joseph Gilder (In Series I), 1887-1888 (Box 92, Folder 2015)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Adolf Rick (In Series I), 1889 (Box 93, Folder 2016)
      Includes letter from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson to Dora Norton Williams
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Margaret Isabella Stevenson (In Series I), 1868-1883 (Box 94, Folder 2017)
    - Letters from Robert Louis Stevenson to Robert Alan Mowbray Stevenson (In Series I), 1868-[1888?] (Box 95, Folder 2018)
    - Letters from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson to Sidney Colvin and Fanny Sitwell (In Series I), 1884-1894 (Box 96, Folder 2019)
    - Letters from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson to Dora Norton Williams (In Series I), 1875-1888 (Box 97, Folder 2020)
    - Letters from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson to Dora Norton Williams (In Series I), 1888-1906 (Box 98, Folder 2021)
    - "Mrs. R. L. Stevenson Lloyd Osbourne Sidney Colvin Correspondence Regarding the Life of Robert Louis Stevenson" I (In Series I), 1895-1899 (Box 99, Folder 2022)
    - "Mrs. R. L. Stevenson Lloyd Osbourne Sidney Colvin Correspondence Regarding the Life of Robert Louis Stevenson" II (In Series I), 1899-1899 (Box 100, Folder 2023)
    - "Mrs. R. L. Stevenson Lloyd Osbourne Sidney Colvin Correspondence Regarding the Life of Robert Louis Stevenson" III (In Series I), 1899-1914 (Box 101, Folder 2024)
    - [Prankster Letters] (5913-5928 and 7936-7938) (In Series I), 1884-1886 (Box 102, Folder 2025)
    - "The Body Snatcher" (6020) (In Series II), undated (Box 103, Folder 2026)
    - Catriona (6078) (In Series II), undated (Box 104, Folder 2027)
    - "The Edifying Letters of the Rutherford Family" (6185) (In Series II), undated (Box 105, Folder 2028)
    - "The Hair Trunk; or, the Ideal Commonwealth, an Extravaganza" (6271) (In Series II), [circa 1876] (Box 106, Folder 2029)
    - In the South Seas [Part IV] (6433) (In Series II), undated (Box 107, Folder 2030)
    - In the South Seas [The Kona Coast] (6435) (In Series II), undated (Box 108, Folder 2031)
    - In the South Seas [Tutuila] (6443-6444) )(In Series II), undated (Box 109, Folder 2032)
    - "Our Lady of the Snows" (6706) (In Series II), undated (Box 110, Folder 2033)
    - Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde (In Series II), undated (Box 111, Folder 2034)
    - The Wrong Box Chapters I-V (7186) (In Series II), undated (Box 112, Folder 2035)
    - The Wrong Box Chapters VI-X (7186) (In Series II), undated (Box 113, Folder 2036)
    - The Wrong Box Chapters XI-XVI (7186) (In Series II), undated (Box 114, Folder 2037)
    - Letters from Katharine D. Osbourne to George S. Hellman (In Series III), 1922-1925 (Box 115, Folder 2038)
    - Letters from [Robert Stevenson] to others (In Series III), 1924-1930 (Box 116, Folder 2039)
    - William Hole water color drawings for Catriona (In Series III), undated (Box 117, Folder 2040)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson artwork (In Series III), [1864-1884] (Box 118, Folder 2041)
    - Material relating to Nerli portrait of Robert Louis Stevenson (In Series III), 1926-1951, undated (Box 119, Folder 2042)
  - Oversize Boxes
    - Letter from Robert Louis Stevenson to the New York Herald Tribune (In Series I), 1882 October 16 (Box 120, Folder 2043)
    - Letters from Edward Livermore Burlingame to Robert Louis Stevenson and others (In Series I), 1887-1894 (Box 120, Folder 2044-2046)
    - Letters from Charles Scribner to Robert Louis Stevenson and others (In Series I), 1887-1894 (Box 120, Folder 2047-2049)
    - "Escape at Bedtime" (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2050)
    - "A Good Boy" (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2051)
    - ["In dreams, unhappy, I behold you stand..."], poem (6406-6410) (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2052)
    - [Indenture] (6449) (In Series II), 1892 April 28 (Box 121, Folder 2053)
    - [Musical Compositions] (6599) (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2054)
    - "My Ship and I," song (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2055)
    - Printed ephemera relating to St. Ives (8353) (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2056)
    - ["She had that peaceful sort of beauty..."] (6836) (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2057)
    - "The Stormy Evening" (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2058)
    - "The Swing," song (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2059)
    - [Tempest Tossed and Sore Afflicted] (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2060)
    - "Windy Nights" (7172) (In Series II), undated (Box 121, Folder 2061)
    - [Contract] by Isobel Field (7370) (In Series II), 1889 May 25 (Box 122, Folder 2062)
    - [Resolution on the Dealth of R.L.S.] by Honolulu Scottish Thistle Club (7253) (In Series II), 1894 December 14 (Box 122, Folder 2063)
    - [Tract of Land Containing Graves...] signed by Thomas Trood (7373) (In Series II), 1896 April 30 (Box 122, Folder 2064)
    - Signatures of Robert Louis Stevenson and others on Union House register (7374) (In Series II), 1888 (Box 122, Folder 2065)
    - [Tailor's Account With R.L.S.] (7391) (In Series II), 1891-1894 (Box 122, Folder 2066)
    - Clipping from Isobel Field letter to Austin Strong (In Series III), 1951 September 23 (Box 122, Folder 2067)
    - Clipping from Edwin J. Beinecke letter to Yale University Library (In Series III), 1966 June 4 (Box 122, Folder 2068)
    - Photographs of Robert Louis Stevenson (In Series III), undated (Box 122, Folder 2069)
    - Photographs of Robert Louis Stevenson with others (In Series III), undated (Box 122, Folder 2070-2072)
    - Photograph of Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (In Series III), undated (Box 123, Folder 2073)
    - Photograph of plaque by Augustus Saint-Gaudens (In Series III), undated (Box 123, Folder 2074)
    - Reproduction of Henry Wolf wood block (In Series III), 1957 (Box 123, Folder 2075)
    - Photograph of Mont St. Helene, California by J. B. Carrington (In Series III), 1920 (Box 123, Folder 2076)
    - Photograph of Robert Louis Stevenson's grave in Samoa (In Series III), 1953 (Box 123, Folder 2077)
    - Disbound album of photographs, artwork by Isobel Field, and clippings relating to Stevenson's life in Samoa (In Series III), undated (Box 123, Folder 2078-2080)
    - Gordon Browne drawings for The Beach of Falesá (In Series III), undated (Box 124, Folder 2081)
    - Timothy Cole engraving of Stevenson (2) (In Series III), undated (Box 124, Folder 2082)
    - Benjamin Greenstein drawing (In Series III), undated (Box 124, Folder 2083)
    - M. Jacques colored print of Barbizon in 1880 (In Series III), undated (Box 124, Folder 2084)
    - Marion Margaret Violet Manners (Duchess of Rutland) drawing of Stevenson (In Series III), 1891 (Box 124, Folder 2085)
    - John Nash pen-and-ink drawings for "Windy Nights" (In Series III), undated (Box 124, Folder 2086)
    - [Joseph?] Simpson colored linoleum cut of Stevenson (In Series III), [1902?] (Box 124, Folder 2087)
    - Joseph Simpson etching of Stevenson (In Series IIII), undated (Box 124, Folder 2088)
    - Folder number 2089 not used. Contents (Robert Louis Stevenson, "Vailima," watercolor) removed to YCAL MSS 1031.
    - George Varian illustrations (3) for Treasure Island (In Series III), 1918, undated (Box 125, Folder 2090-2092)
    - R. Canton Woodville pen-and-ink drawing for "The Great North Road" (In Series III), undated (Box 125, Folder 2093)
    - S. J. Woolf portrait of Stevenson (In Series III), undated (Box 125, Folder 2094)
    - Unidentified artwork, including pen-and-ink illustrations for The Black Arrow (In Series III), undated (Box 125, Folder 2095-2100)
    - Foster Bros. copy print of painting of Stevenson (In Series III), undated (Box 126, Folder 2101)
    - Robert Bryden woodcut of Stevenson (In Series III), [1901?] (Box 126, Folder 2102)
    - [Thomas?] Johnson etchings (2) of Stevenson (In Series III), undated (Box 126, Folder 2103)
    - Clippings (In Series III), 1888-1962, undated (Box 126, Folder 2104-2106)
    - Article on Stevenson in El Paso Times (In Series IV), 1935 January 6 (Box 126, Folder 2107)
    - Article on Stevenson in New York Times Book Review (In Series IV), 1941 January 12 (Box 126, Folder 2108)
    - Clippings from Clayton Meeker Hamilton letter to Sidney Colvin (In Series IV), 1923 Janury 28 (Box 126, Folder 2109)
    - Clippings (In Series IV), 1893-1949 (Box 126, Folder 2110)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson's chess set (In Series III), undated (Box 127, Folder 2111)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson's flageolet (In Series III), undated (Box 127, Folder 2112)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson's paper cutter (In Series III), undated (Box 127, Folder 2113)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson's candlestick holders (In Series III), undated (Box 128, Folder 2114)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson's pipe (In Series III), undated (Box 128, Folder 2115)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson's wood engraving tools and blocks (In Series III), undated (Box 129, Folder 2116)
    - Empty envelopes (In Series III), 1953, undated (Box 130, Folder 2117-2121)
    - Printed ephemera (In Series III), 1879-1963 (Box 130, Folder 2122-2124)
    - Scrapbook (In Series III), 1880-1939, undated (Box 131, Folder 2125)
    - Scrapbook (In Series III), 1911-1935, undated (Box 132, Folder 2126)
    - Scrapbook (In Series III), [1865]-1940, undated (Box 133, Folder 2127)